Church Women United in Tucson collection, 1963-2003
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Church Women United in Tucson collection, 1963-2003
MS 427
Church Women United in Tucson
Papers (1963-2003). This collection contains materials relating to Church Women United in Tucson (CWUT), a non-denominational organization which began in the late 1940s dedicated to promoting world peace and justice through community programs, events, and celebrations. Materials include administrative documents such as annual reports/meetings, the award certificate for Church Women United Day, bylaws, logo clip sheets, member directories, and a training manual; publications including member obituaries, the CWTU newsletter, news clippings, press releases, and programs; as well as a small set of photographs. All materials are in English.
1.25 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Biographical Note
Church Women United began on a national level in 1941 with the mission to promote world peace and justice through community service projects including the organization of programs, events, and annual celebrations. Since then the organization has expanded to include more than 1,200 local and state branches. Church Women United in Tucson (CWUT), created in the late 1940s, supports the national organization's mission and goals through its work with the Tucson community.
The CWUT organizes three annual celebration days for the Tucson area, which are also celebrated on both a national and international level: the World Day of Prayer in March, May Friendship Day in May, and World Community Day in November. Various community service programs including: Migrant Ministry, Farm Labor and Indian Ministry, Marana Health Clinic, Families for International Friendship (FFIF), Tucson Ecumenical Council, Women in Community Service/ Job Corps, Habitat for Humanity, Armory Park Low Income Housing, Tucson Centers for Women and Children, Youth on their Own and the Healthy Arizona Initiative have been created, initialized, or first brought to Tucson by the CWUT.
Organization
This collection is organized into 3 series:
Series I: Administrative Files, 1964-2001
Series 2: Publications, 1963-2003
Series 3: Photographs, 1984
Scope and Content Note
Papers (1963-2003). This collection contains the Administrative Files and Publications of the Church Women United in Tucson organization (CWUT). The CWUT is a local branch of the national Church Women United organization; it is a non-denominational organization which began in the late 1940s dedicated to promoting world peace and justice through community service such as social services programs and annual celebrations. Materials include Administrative Documents: annual reports/meetings, the award certificate for Church Women United Day, bylaws, logo clip sheets, member directories, and a training manual; Publications: member obituaries, the CWTU newsletter, news clippings, press releases, and programs; and Photographs: a 1984 special meeting in Phoenix. Of special interest is the award certificate presented to the organization from the city of Tucson in honor of Church Women United Day in 1991. All materials are in English.
Access Terms
Church Women United (Tucson, Ariz.).
National Council of the Churches of Christ in the United States of America. Dept. of United Church Women.
Women in Community Service (U.S.)
Container List
- Series 1: Administrative Files 1964-2001
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains the CWUT Annual Reports and Meetings from 1964-1999; the award certificate presented to the CWUT by the city of Tucson proclaiming January 14, 1991 as Church Women United Day; the organization bylaws; CWUT logo clip sheets; member directories from 1964-2001; and a training manual from a 1987 CWU Southwest Regional Intensive Leadership Development training.
  - Annual Reports/Meetings. 1964-1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Reports/Meetings. 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Award Certificate - Church Women United Day. 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bylaws. undated, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Logo Clip Sheets. undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Memeber Directories. 1964-2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Training Manual. 1987 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series 2: Publications, 1963-2003
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains prominent CWUT member obituaries, both news clippings and funeral programs; the CWTU monthly newsletter; news clippings, mostly event notices in the religious/church calendar of Tucson newspapers; press releases, for both radio stations and newspapers; programs for CWUT annual events such as Christmas in September, May Fellowship Day, and World Community Day; programs for the organization's Jubilee in 1991, and a program information packet for the 1997 CWUT Southwest Regional Event.
  - Member Obituaries. 1984-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Newsletter. 1963-2003 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - News Clippings. 1978-1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Press Releases. undated, 1978-1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Press Releases. 1987-1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Programs - Annual Events. 1984-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Programs - Jubilee. 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Programs - Southwest Regional Event. 1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Series 3: Photographs, 1984
  Arrangement: Alphabetical. This series contains a small set of photographs of a 1984 special meeting in Phoenix. Also included is a letter with brief information regarding the event.
  - Special Meeting with Thelma Adina - First Church of the Brethren, Phoenix. 1984 (Box 1, Folder 16)